<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>verification on Dominic Mulligan</title>
    <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/verification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in verification on Dominic Mulligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Dominic Mulligan, 2020&amp;ndash;2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 19:49:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/verification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accepted TYPES 2022 post-proceedings paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/types-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 19:49:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/types-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper All watched over by machines of loving grace, describing the Supervisionary proof-checking system for HOL, has been accepted in the post-proceedings of TYPES 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted OOPSLA/SPLASH 2023 paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oopsla-2023-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oopsla-2023-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;A verification methodology for the Arm Confidential Computing Architecture&amp;rdquo; co-written with Anthony Fox, Gareth Stockwell, Shale Xiong, Hanno Becker, Nathan Chong, and Gustavo Petri has now been accepted for publication at OOPSLA/SPLASH 2023.
The PDF of the final version of the paper is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted OSCAR 2022 workshop paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oscar-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:41:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oscar-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that the abstract, &amp;ldquo;Scalable assurance via verifiable hardware-software contracts&amp;rdquo;, has been accepted for presentation at the Workshop on Open-source Computer Architecture Research (OSCAR 2022), co-located with ISCA. This was co-written with Yao Hsiao, Gustavo Petri, Nikos Nikoleris, and Caroline Trippel, with Yao presenting this work at the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted PriSC 2022 workshop paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/prisc-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/prisc-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that &amp;ldquo;The Supervisionary proof-checking kernel, or: a work-in-progress towards proof-generating code&amp;rdquo;, which I co-authored with Nick Spinale, has been accepted for presentation at the workshop on Principles of Secure Compilation (PriSC 2022), co-located with POPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:40:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am please to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;A highly-available move operation for replicated trees&amp;rdquo; has now been accepted for publication at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS). This is joint work with Martin Kleppmann, Victor Gomes, and Alastair Beresford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE/ACM MICRO 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:35:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;Synthesizing formal models of hardware from RTL for efficient verification of memory model implementations&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication at the IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO) 2021. This is a paper co-written with Yao Hsiao (Stanford), Gustavo Petri (Arm Research), Nikos Nikoleris (Arm Research), and Caroline Trippel (Stanford).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
