<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dominic Mulligan</title>
    <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dominic Mulligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Dominic Mulligan, 2020&amp;ndash;2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 20:03:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accepted IEEE TETCSI special issue paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/tetcsi-2023-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 20:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/tetcsi-2023-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper Private delegated computations using strong isolation has been accepted into a special issue on advances in emerging privacy-preserving computation at IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computer Science (TETCSI). The paper was coauthored with Mathias Brossard, Guilhem Bryant, Basma El Gaabouri, Xinxin Fan, Alexandre Ferreira, Edmund Grimley-Evans, Christopher Haster, Evan Johnson, Derek Miller, Fan Mo, Nick Spinale, Eric van Hensbergen, Hugo J. M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted TYPES 2022 post-proceedings paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/types-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 19:49:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/types-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper All watched over by machines of loving grace, describing the Supervisionary proof-checking system for HOL, has been accepted in the post-proceedings of TYPES 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted OOPSLA/SPLASH 2023 paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oopsla-2023-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oopsla-2023-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;A verification methodology for the Arm Confidential Computing Architecture&amp;rdquo; co-written with Anthony Fox, Gareth Stockwell, Shale Xiong, Hanno Becker, Nathan Chong, and Gustavo Petri has now been accepted for publication at OOPSLA/SPLASH 2023.
The PDF of the final version of the paper is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Arm, and a new job at AWS</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/leaving-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 14:14:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/leaving-arm/</guid>
      <description>I have now left Arm Research and will be taking up a position as a Principal Applied Scientist within the Automated Reasoning Group at AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arm Trustworthy AI whitepaper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/arm-trustworthy-ai-whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:55:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/arm-trustworthy-ai-whitepaper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce the recent publication of the Arm Trustworthy AI position paper, a documented which I contributed to. You can read the whitepaper here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New technical report on the Icecap and Veracruz projects</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/icecap-veracruz-technical-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:55:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/icecap-veracruz-technical-report/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce the recent release of an Arm Research technical report on the IceCap and Veracruz confidential-computing projects. The report, &amp;ldquo;Private delegated computations using strong isolation&amp;rdquo;, is co-authored by Mathias Brossard, Guilhem Bryant, Basma El Gaabouri, Xinxin Fan, Alexandre Ferreira, Edmund Grimley-Evans, Christopher Haster, Evan Johnson, Derek Miller, Fan Mo, Nick Spinale, Eric van Hensbergen, Hugo J. M. Vincent, Shale Xiong, and me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted OSCAR 2022 workshop paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oscar-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:41:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oscar-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that the abstract, &amp;ldquo;Scalable assurance via verifiable hardware-software contracts&amp;rdquo;, has been accepted for presentation at the Workshop on Open-source Computer Architecture Research (OSCAR 2022), co-located with ISCA. This was co-written with Yao Hsiao, Gustavo Petri, Nikos Nikoleris, and Caroline Trippel, with Yao presenting this work at the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All papers moved from previous homepage</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/all-papers-moved/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 14:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/all-papers-moved/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce that electronic copies of all of my papers have now been moved over from my old website and can be found under &amp;ldquo;Publications&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted PriSC 2022 workshop paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/prisc-2022-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/prisc-2022-paper/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that &amp;ldquo;The Supervisionary proof-checking kernel, or: a work-in-progress towards proof-generating code&amp;rdquo;, which I co-authored with Nick Spinale, has been accepted for presentation at the workshop on Principles of Secure Compilation (PriSC 2022), co-located with POPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OC3 programme committee invite</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</guid>
      <description>I am honoured to have been invited to serve on the Open Confidential Computing Conference (OC3 2021) programme committee. Please, consider submitting a talk proposal! Derek Miller, from the Veracruz project, presented a talk at last year&amp;rsquo;s OC3 event which had a great mix of interesting talks and was very well attended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:40:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am please to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;A highly-available move operation for replicated trees&amp;rdquo; has now been accepted for publication at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS). This is joint work with Martin Kleppmann, Victor Gomes, and Alastair Beresford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at FICS, the University of Florida</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Prof. Kevin Butler for inviting me to give a keynote talk at the Technical Demo Conference within the Florida Institute for Cybersecurity Research (FICS) at the University of Florida. My slides for the talk—Confidential Computing: Brave New World— are available here in Microsoft PowerPoint format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE/ACM MICRO 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:35:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;Synthesizing formal models of hardware from RTL for efficient verification of memory model implementations&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication at the IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO) 2021. This is a paper co-written with Yao Hsiao (Stanford), Gustavo Petri (Arm Research), Nikos Nikoleris (Arm Research), and Caroline Trippel (Stanford).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited paper at IEEE SEED 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:23:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce a new paper&amp;mdash;an invited contribution from industry&amp;mdash;accepted at the IEEE International Symposium on Secure and Private Execution Environment Design (SEED 2021): &amp;ldquo;Seeds of SEED: Confidential Computing&amp;mdash;a brave new world&amp;rdquo;. This was written with some of my colleagues at Arm: Gustavo Petri, Nick Spinale, Gareth Stockwell, and Hugo Vincent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-preserving collaborative compute with Veracruz</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 23:11:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</guid>
      <description>Veracruz is a project that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for a while internally within Arm Research. Recently, Veracruz was released as an open-source project on Github, with all development and design discussions moving into the open. This was a precursor to the project being adopted by the Linux Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Confidential Computing Consortium (CCC), which I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say finally happened a few weeks ago, at the beginning of April.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain a little bit more about the project and what its motivation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications list</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/publications-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 16:21:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/publications-list/</guid>
      <description>I have now moved my bibliography over from my old website. The list can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Homepage</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/new-homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 12:05:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/new-homepage/</guid>
      <description>Due to increasing unreliability of my website host, and regular security issues with WordPress, I have moved to a static site hosted on Github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
