<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>veracruz on Dominic Mulligan</title>
    <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/veracruz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in veracruz on Dominic Mulligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Dominic Mulligan, 2020–2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 19:10:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/veracruz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supervisionary: the idea</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/supervisionary-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 19:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/supervisionary-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>Nick Spinale and I recently submitted a short talk abstract to the Principles of Secure Compilation (PriSC) workshop, co-located with POPL 2022. The abstract, which was thankfully accepted for presentation, describes some ideas that Nick and I have been discussing for a while. I&amp;rsquo;ll use this post to flesh the abstract out and explain the design of the prototype Supervisionary proof-checking system which Nick and I have been working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OC3 programme committee invite</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</guid>
      <description>I am honoured to have been invited to serve on the Open Confidential Computing Conference (OC3 2021) programme committee. Please, consider submitting a talk proposal! Derek Miller, from the Veracruz project, presented a talk at last year&amp;rsquo;s OC3 event which had a great mix of interesting talks and was very well attended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at FICS, the University of Florida</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Prof. Kevin Butler for inviting me to give a keynote talk at the Technical Demo Conference within the Florida Institute for Cybersecurity Research (FICS) at the University of Florida. My slides for the talk—Confidential Computing: Brave New World— are available here in Microsoft PowerPoint format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited paper at IEEE SEED 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:23:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce a new paper&amp;mdash;an invited contribution from industry&amp;mdash;accepted at the IEEE International Symposium on Secure and Private Execution Environment Design (SEED 2021): &amp;ldquo;Seeds of SEED: Confidential Computing&amp;mdash;a brave new world&amp;rdquo;. This was written with some of my colleagues at Arm: Gustavo Petri, Nick Spinale, Gareth Stockwell, and Hugo Vincent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-preserving collaborative compute with Veracruz</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 23:11:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</guid>
      <description>Veracruz is a project that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for a while internally within Arm Research. Recently, Veracruz was released as an open-source project on Github, with all development and design discussions moving into the open. This was a precursor to the project being adopted by the Linux Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Confidential Computing Consortium (CCC), which I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say finally happened a few weeks ago, at the beginning of April.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain a little bit more about the project and what its motivation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
