<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dominic Mulligan</title>
    <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dominic Mulligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Dominic Mulligan, 2020–2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:59:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominicpm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OC3 programme committee invite</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 13:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/oc3-programme-committee/</guid>
      <description>I am honoured to have been invited to serve on the Open Confidential Computing Conference (OC3 2021) programme committee. Please, consider submitting a talk proposal! Derek Miller, from the Veracruz project, presented a talk at last year&amp;rsquo;s OC3 event which had a great mix of interesting talks and was very well attended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:40:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/ieee-tpds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am please to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;A highly-available move operation for replicated trees&amp;rdquo; has now been accepted for publication at IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS). This is joint work with Martin Kleppmann, Victor Gomes, and Alastair Beresford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at FICS, the University of Florida</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/florida-fics2021-invited-talk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Prof. Kevin Butler for inviting me to give a keynote talk at the Technical Demo Conference within the Florida Institute for Cybersecurity Research (FICS) at the University of Florida. My slides for the talk—Confidential Computing: Brave New World— are available here in Microsoft PowerPoint format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted paper at IEEE/ACM MICRO 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:35:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/micro-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce that the paper &amp;ldquo;Synthesizing formal models of hardware from RTL for efficient verification of memory model implementations&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication at the IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO) 2021. This is a paper co-written with Yao Hsiao (Stanford), Gustavo Petri (Arm Research), Nikos Nikoleris (Arm Research), and Caroline Trippel (Stanford).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited paper at IEEE SEED 2021</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:23:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/seeds-2021-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce a new paper&amp;mdash;an invited contribution from industry&amp;mdash;accepted at the IEEE International Symposium on Secure and Private Execution Environment Design (SEED 2021): &amp;ldquo;Seeds of SEED: Confidential Computing&amp;mdash;a brave new world&amp;rdquo;. This was written with some of my colleagues at Arm: Gustavo Petri, Nick Spinale, Gareth Stockwell, and Hugo Vincent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cbmc Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/cbmc-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 11:03:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/cbmc-introduction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-preserving collaborative compute with Veracruz</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 23:11:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/veracruz/</guid>
      <description>Veracruz is a project that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for a while internally within Arm Research. Recently, Veracruz was released as an open-source project on Github, with all development and design discussions moving into the open. This was a precursor to the project being adopted by the Linux Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Confidential Computing Consortium (CCC), which I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say finally happened a few weeks ago, at the beginning of April.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain a little bit more about the project and what its motivation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications list</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/publications-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 16:21:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/publications-list/</guid>
      <description>I have now moved my bibliography over from my old website. The list can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 13:14:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Click here for my DBLP entry and here for my Google Scholar entry.
Journals  A highly-available move operation for replicated trees. Martin Kleppmann, Dominic P. Mulligan, Victor Gomes, and Alastair Beresford. IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems. In press, 2021. PDF Permissive nominal terms and their unification: an infinite, coinfinite approach to nominal techniques. Gilles Dowek, Murdoch J. Gabbay, and Dominic P. Mulligan. Logic Journal of the Interest Group in Pure Logic, volume 18, issue 6, pages 769–822, 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Homepage</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/new-homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 12:05:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/new-homepage/</guid>
      <description>Due to increasing unreliability of my website host, and regular security issues with WordPress, I have moved to a static site hosted on Github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Principal Research Engineer within the Security Group at Arm Research, UK. My current research focuses within Arm are privacy-preserving computation and correctness for low-level, security-critical software.
Prior to joining Arm, I was a postdoctoral research scientist, first at the Dipartimento di Scienze dell&amp;rsquo;Informazione at the University of Bologna, and later at the Computer Laboratory at the University of Cambridge. I worked on the specification and verification of low-level systems software, such as C compilers and ELF linkers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
