<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>icecap on Dominic Mulligan</title>
    <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/icecap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in icecap on Dominic Mulligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Dominic Mulligan, 2020&amp;ndash;2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 20:03:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominicpm.github.io/tags/icecap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accepted IEEE TETCSI special issue paper</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/tetcsi-2023-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 20:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/tetcsi-2023-paper/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that the paper Private delegated computations using strong isolation has been accepted into a special issue on advances in emerging privacy-preserving computation at IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computer Science (TETCSI). The paper was coauthored with Mathias Brossard, Guilhem Bryant, Basma El Gaabouri, Xinxin Fan, Alexandre Ferreira, Edmund Grimley-Evans, Christopher Haster, Evan Johnson, Derek Miller, Fan Mo, Nick Spinale, Eric van Hensbergen, Hugo J. M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New technical report on the Icecap and Veracruz projects</title>
      <link>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/icecap-veracruz-technical-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:55:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicpm.github.io/posts/icecap-veracruz-technical-report/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce the recent release of an Arm Research technical report on the IceCap and Veracruz confidential-computing projects. The report, &amp;ldquo;Private delegated computations using strong isolation&amp;rdquo;, is co-authored by Mathias Brossard, Guilhem Bryant, Basma El Gaabouri, Xinxin Fan, Alexandre Ferreira, Edmund Grimley-Evans, Christopher Haster, Evan Johnson, Derek Miller, Fan Mo, Nick Spinale, Eric van Hensbergen, Hugo J. M. Vincent, Shale Xiong, and me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
